hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast if we haven't met
yet my name is jeremiah krakowski and on
this podcast we'll talk about ways for
you to grow in your life and your
business to make more money reach your
goals and live the life of your dreams
if you're a course speaker if you're a
coach and you want to know what does it
take to make six figures or even seven
figures online that's what i help you do
i've been in this industry for the last
19 years helping course creators coaches
trainers and mentors scale their
businesses to get as many clients and
customers as possible and so you're in
the right place now today we're gonna
talk about a question that has come up i
just launched my brand new group
coaching program this week so excited we
have so many people that have jumped
into the program and dozens more that
have told me that they're going to be
jumping in later on this week
oh my goodness the questions the
feedback that have come in is great one
of the number one questions i've
actually never gotten this question
before until now is okay i know that i
want to do coaching
i know that i want to make courses i
know that i want to make money online
but
how
do i know what my niche is how do i know
what to focus on how do i know what to
talk about okay so before we're gonna go
into that i'm gonna explain the uh the
interesting background here
i'm actually in in one of the side rooms
in our house one of the guest rooms
because there's a bunch of people doing
stuff around my house and i waited until
the last minute to record this and so
you got to make do with what you got so
if you're watching the video version it
might look a little bit weird
there's like a
an emu or something or a moose or
whatever that animal is sleeping on a
couch up there
on the wall okay
so now
if you are somebody you say i want to
make more money in a business online i
want to
create a course i know that coaching and
courses is a great way to make money but
what should my niche be what should i do
now if you're like i don't know what to
sell
i have other episodes on that
so if you're like i don't know what to
sell online at all you're not wanting to
do courses or coaching
uh episode number 152 i believe it is
it's grow your life
152.
uh nope that one's on overcoming
perfectionism
around there i should have
an episode that's all about
what um the best
online businesses are that you could do
episode 150
ideas for online businesses that you can
start in 2022 okay so that episode right
there is a great place to start i'm
going to put the link in the description
of this post if you're like i don't know
if i want to do courses or coaching this
is going to give you ideas
for businesses that you can do online
okay
now
if you are going to choose courses of
coaching here's why i would say this i
recommend it because it's the fastest
way to make six figures and seven
figures it really is without needing a
whole lot of overhead without needing to
create physical products
and you can do so from anywhere
you can do so with just a computer an
internet an internet connection or even
just a cell phone and an internet
connection
you don't need
a whole bunch of
complex stuff to successfully have a
business in that niche
and in my experience
this is what i've helped people with the
most is in that niche is i've helped
create multiple eight figure
coaching programs and so if you're
learning from me specifically
i'm going to really show you how to
maximize the coaching and the course
creation niche above everything else if
you want to do another niche you're
still going to find a lot of value for
my training because it's about getting
customers it's about getting people to
buy from you okay
but specifically okay i'm going to coach
people i'm going to create a course
there's a course in my members area if
you're part of my accelerator
there's a course in the accelerator
called easy course creation blueprint
where i walk you through step by step
everything that you need to know on how
to put together a course okay so if
you're like okay i want to make a course
on this topic that course is literally
the the the blueprint on how to make a
course i i've created i think 30 courses
and from that i put everything that i
know about making courses into that one
for you okay
uh then my other course transformational
coaching made simple that you get as
well with the accelerator is all about
creating a coaching program and coaching
programs is really
where the maximum level of profit is
found is how you can scale things to
that level because you're adding so much
higher value with a coaching program
because you're able to come alongside
people you're not just giving them
information you're able to come
alongside them support them and help
them so the value of what you offer goes
up when you add coaching to it
i've sold my courses for
uh five hundred dollars a thousand
dollars but the value goes up even more
when i add coaching to it and so that's
why now with my accelerator over my
website you get
all of my courses now
for less than the price of one of my
courses plus coaching you get coaching
with me where i work with you where you
get calls with me and so if you're not
in the accelerator consider joining that
i think it would really help you i think
if you're somebody that is a course
creator if you're a coach
the client growth accelerator
is the number one resource out there
today i truly believe that i stand by it
it's a 30 day money back guarantee i
believe in it so much i literally let
you jump into the program go through
everything and if it's not for you great
well part ways at the end of 30 days
i think it's the best resource if you
are a course creator or a coach to get
results to get more clients
in a business now
you might say great that's great or
you're listing this you say i'm already
in the program jeremiah but i want to
know what should i make my course or
coaching program about
that's what this is going to be this is
going to be the foundational kind of
training and i and i plan on using this
podcast episode as when people ask me
hey what should i make a program about
i'm going to send them this link to this
video okay so let's dive into this
when you are coaching people
you are
finding a group of people let's let's
break down what coaching and courses are
actually
your coaching is you find a group of
people that need
your help
to reach a goal that they have okay
how do you discover that goal well you
end up connecting with people that have
problems
and so in the beginning most people are
going to struggle to know exactly
what that is that they should help
people with and i get that and and
that's normal and that's that's part of
the process so don't don't feel
overwhelmed if you're like man i don't
know what to make a coaching program on
i'm going to give you a testimony from
myself right here so i had built an
eight-figure coaching program with my
mom
and i started this business in 2018 and
i said you know what i'm gonna help
people make websites my very first
course was website building
turns out
that really wasn't the niche that i was
meant to be in so i've created a
advertising course turns out
ads really isn't the niche that i want
to be in
and and what i realized is
everybody who was coming to me for help
was usually 99 of the time
a coach
or a course creator
and my own background was in that
industry okay
so i was able to take my own background
and what people were coming to me for
to create my business around and this is
this is where a lot of people they're
like okay well what could i do what
could i do i've only worked a corporate
job or i want to do this
here's the first thing
don't be afraid to change it later so
that's going to be one of the biggest
pieces of advice i can give you
is if you choose a niche now
don't be afraid
to change the niche later because you
learned
new information okay
you can get a lot of input from what you
see other people doing
for courses or coaching if you're in the
accelerator
there's a ton of coaches and course
creators in there and you can see okay
maybe that's a niche that i want to get
into
you see what i'm saying
so that jogs your memory and gives you
ideas on that
there's also some questions that you can
answer that can help you okay
and these are actually taken from the
course irresistible offers that sell
i tell most people to go through this to
figure out what their first offer is
specifically
and you figure that out by answering
some of these questions
what are you passionate about
what do you love
what what are you good at
what skills do you bring to the table
okay
i want you to write these down like what
are you good at what are you passionate
about
and what are you passionate about and
good at that relates to or helps
other people
okay
you can build a coaching program around
that literally you could build a
coaching program around helping people
get better at video games
around helping people
do their hair better around helping
people with their car
around helping people with a number of
different things
it does it's not it doesn't have to be
difficult
there's so many different
um
angles that you can take on this
and and i'm actually going to pull up a
list here um
i found this the other day of some
different like niches
vegetable gardening marketing consulting
yoga stretching
drawing artwork
home bakery creating apps simply
creating websites trauma coaching life
coaching teaching people how to create
courses themselves so these are all
niches right here
that a lot of people you know a lot of
the people who learn from me they'll do
health coaching or they'll do
fitness or they will teach marketing or
they'll teach social media content
creation
you name it these different topics can
then be marketable
to the market and here's the cool thing
you don't have to be an expert on it
today
tomorrow
you you only have to learn a few things
that a lot of people don't know let me
explain that a little bit better okay
see a lot of people think oh i got to be
this this big expert before i could
create a course or a coaching program
you don't
you don't have to have 19 years
experience like me and and here's
another thing that i'll share with you
you can learn from other experts and
then help other people with what you
learned from those experts
i'm an expert that you could do that
with
so you could take what you learned from
me
and help coach other people
on the same stuff that you learned from
me
and you could build a coaching program
around that and you could actually build
your own coaching program where people
still have to even sign up for my
program as part of it and then you
teach and coach them on your own on the
topic this is a great way anybody who's
in my accelerator could actually
instantly start a coaching program just
by helping teach people and being a
coach
of what i'm teaching
case in point or you could learn from
any number of people on youtube or books
or courses that are out there a lot of
you have gone through a number of
different courses over the years and you
have a lot of information but you say
why would anybody learn from me listen
here's the thing the first thing that's
so important when it comes to
actually selling yourself
as a course creator as a coach is you
got to believe in yourself
you got to believe that you have value
to offer the marketplace
that you have strategic value that you
can bring to people
and that
not thinking of yourself as i'm little
me i'm not as good as other people stop
comparing yourself to other people stop
comparing yourself to what other people
have done
everybody has to start somewhere when i
started with what i know all i knew how
to do was edit videos
that's it
how did i get into this niche
i edited videos for people
that were
coaches and trainers in the sales
industry and i learned skills that i
didn't know before
and through that trial and error and
testing i grew my skill set and now i
teach other people what i've learned
what are things that you've learned in
your lifetime that you could share
and coach other people on
or what are things that you could learn
in the next six months to a year
that you could coach other people on
these are two great ways
to be able to find what your niche is
okay and here's the essential thing
you're essentially pulling people up who
are a little bit behind where you are
so you might say well i'm not an expert
on this topic jeremiah i'm not an ex
expert at this thing you don't have to
be
you don't have to be
you just have to know a little bit more
than some other people
and then you market to those other
people that know a little bit less than
you do about that topic you see how
simple that is i'm sure that there's a
number of things that you know a little
bit more of than other people do about
certain things in fact if you have
experience in corporate america you
might know some really great strategies
that you've learned in the marketplace
that you could translate directly into a
coaching program or a course
you might say well i still don't feel
confident enough to put it out there
well
that's where again i mention growing in
your self-confidence growing in your
self-esteem
we are taught and raised as people by
our parents by businesses that we're in
by companies that we work for to not
feel self-confident
because it makes us easier to control
that's a bomb right that's a big one
everybody can feel that especially if
you've ever had somebody put you down
and made you not feel good enough
school system even does that
so you have to develop inside of
yourself that level of self belief
that level of self confidence
to then say okay you know what it's not
perfect but i'm gonna record a course
i'm gonna i'm gonna go through
jeremiah's program i'm gonna record a
course on this topic might not be the
perfect topic
but i'm gonna put it out there i'm gonna
record a two hour training in maybe four
modules
just sharing my thoughts on a certain
topic and i'm gonna sell it to people
for for
two hundred dollars or five hundred
dollars and see how many people buy it
and that right there is how you break
into the course creation and coaching
industry
and yet so many people are over thinking
and over analyzing what i just shared
with you
it's not that complicated
it's not that difficult
you just have to take the first steps to
move forward instead of talking yourself
out of it instead of letting what's
between your two ears convince you that
you're not good enough that you have to
get to a certain level before you can
and just start now with what you got
just start now with what's in front of
you now you might say well i wish i had
a better blueprint again
if you're in my accelerator
those two courses transformational
coaching made simple
and easy course creation blueprint those
two courses literally walk you through
how to create a coaching program and how
to create your first course
okay
i tell you how to come up with those
ideas
how to come up with what idea you should
create a course on
in that okay
and so if you're like well okay i have
an idea great if you have somewhat of an
idea by this point
there it is now if you still don't have
any idea
here's what i would invite you to do
here's a little exercise of how to break
past the muck inside your head
go for a walk
10 minutes 20 minutes
get your body moving
maybe eat something beforehand so you
don't pass out
and i want you to
just think about
what would i create a course or coaching
program on while you go for a walk
and you might have to do this for a
couple days couple times
i'm telling you this is literally a
strategy that i use
and that my clients have used that
produces results like like this is gonna
break you out of the stuckness
go for a walk
and when an idea pops in your head of
maybe i could coach on that
maybe i could teach on that
write it down don't go into well maybe
i'm not good enough well maybe i don't
know enough well maybe i'm not at the
right level yet
don't even let your brain go into that
because it's gonna want to okay
write down a list of those ideas
and then
take that list of ideas
go for a walk again or do something
put it aside
come back to it a day or two later
and decide which one of those ideas
really stands out to you
i'm telling you
if you do this
you will get clarity on what your niche
should be
you will get clarity on doing that
literally most people
if you listen to this episode and you
haven't done that exercise that i just
gave you
i don't know much
what to say on how to help you at this
point
because you're literally choosing to not
do what works
and so
try it out go for a walk write some
ideas down
the reason i say go for a walk so
walking has been found too instead of
like meditating sitting in a chair and
meditating walking is a form of
meditation mentally the brain ends up
firing in a very similar way and so what
ends up happening is when you're
focusing on one idea
specifically and you're looking at
nature and stuff like this
it cuts through a lot of the weeds in
your brain
just by going through for a walk
and it'll help you make decisions better
oftentimes when i'm stuck on making a
hard decision i will go for a walk or i
will go for a 30 minute drive in my car
driving in a car thing you ever notice
you get the best ideas in the shower
or in a car or stuff like that it's
literally because the
the mental state that you go into is
conducive of cutting through a lot of
the overthinking
and that's actually where you come up
with your best ideas
okay
and so
answering those questions what am i
passionate about what skills do i have
how can i help others or what skills do
i want to learn to help others with
and then you can figure out okay is
there a market for this
what is the biggest problem and
frustration that this market has
and what solution and outcome can i
bring to their life okay so here's the
biggest problem in frustration that
course creators and coaches have that i
found
getting customers to pay them money
honestly this part of it that we're
talking about right here
finding your niche and creating the
course is actually
the easy part
it really is
you don't want to spend a whole lot of
time doing that part of it you really
want to minimize that amount of time of
actually this part of it because the
real work is getting customers
and so the solution that i solve is i
teach people how to get customers
the right way
how to adjust their messaging how to
adjust your copy how to create offers
that people can't say no to okay
and then you want to figure out okay is
what i'm here's is what i'm going to
offer am i going to be doing something
for somebody is it a service that you're
going to offer
your offer could be a service
am i going to do it with them or is it
going to be do it yourself
so a course is always do it yourself
a coaching program is always done with
you
and then done for you is i have twenty
thousand dollar a month clients where i
do their marketing for them at 20 000 a
month
how are we making
consistently multiple six and seven
figures
this is how
this model right here
okay
and so when you identify what is that
thing and and here's another thing i
want to invite you to do you might you
might say well
everything's all been done before
i want to do something unique that
nobody's done before
here's what sets you apart is that you
are uniquely yourself you are not like
anybody else
and so are there other people that teach
coaching and courses out there yes there
are but they're not me and i think i'm
the best at doing it
i think i'm one of the best people out
there at this very thing and so that's
why i confidently
know that i can help pull somebody up to
the level of making six and seven and
even eight figures
in the coaching and course industry
that's what i promise with my coaching
program that's what i help people do
so what what is it though that you can
do that you can help guide people on the
process of doing now you might say well
i've never done it before
you know jeremiah you've done it for so
long i've never done it before well
start with one person help bring
positive impact to one
person and build your case studies that
way
you know when i started in this business
i had been working with my mom and we
had built an eight-figure coaching
program
and
she had told me i couldn't use any of
the
customers any of the people that we had
worked with i couldn't use any of the
email list i couldn't claim that i was
had
built that business
i had to start from scratch just like
everybody else
with this business and build up brand
new case studies from scratch was it
hard it was it was difficult it took a
grind in the beginning but now we have
dozens of case studies of people that
we've helped make money with their
coaching and courses making seven
figures making six figures
and so with that
it all starts with
taking the first step
for some of you taking that first step
is going to be jumping into my coaching
program the accelerator over my website
jeremiahkowski.com
forward slash accelerator
to help you get into an environment of
people that are working on a same goal
together
and then go through those courses easy
course creation blueprint irresistible
offers that sell transformational
coaching
get on one of the live coaching calls
and ask questions
be interacting in the group posting in
the group
asking questions along the way anywhere
that you get stuck i want you to think
about at the end of watching this
podcast episode
what questions in you did this inspire
in you
then go ask me those questions on my
social media
and i'll help guide you from there
okay
it just takes the first step
it just takes starting from where you're
at and i think that anybody can build a
full-time income
in coaching in courses you know if
they've never done it before
with what i just shared with you on this
podcast episode and some of you might
have to listen to this episode over and
over again to really start to get it
again i tell you that exercise of going
for a walk
writing it down is really going to help
you all right
listen if this has helped you
please consider jumping into the
accelerator the client growth
accelerator
[Music]
no more waiting no more sitting on the
fence of saying
maybe i'd like to build a business maybe
i'd like to make a full-time income as a
course creator as a coach it's time to
step out of the boat and step into
what's possible for you
i'll see you in there we'll talk soon